Nestor Jesus Ramirez Reyes

Veracruz, México | 2293673599 | nesjesramrey@gmail.com

My profile

I'm a Data Analysis and Scientist with 18 years as financial and accountant, I like it to analysis data and investigate the best way to improve the results in the companies, I think the tech tools give us best results with a few resources, I improved the sales, revenues utilities and cost in the places that I have worked.

Experience

DATA SCIENTIS | CODERHOUSE | JUN 2022 TO PRESENT

- Teach the topics about the course the data science for beginners
- · Give feedback each student
- · Solve questions and help students with their problems
- · Practice and doing models with the datasets

DEVELOPER JR | KODEMIA | FEBRUARY 2022 TO AUGUST 2022

- · Development a Project with MERN(MongoDB, Express, React and Nodejs).
- · Design the mockups and wireframes for the web app
- · Worked with Scrum methodologies
- · Deploy the API in AWS EC2 services
- · Deploy Frontend in Vercel
- https://menus-world.vercel.app/

CONTROLLER | DIESTRA | DECEMBER 2008 TO JANUARY 2022

- Financial analysis the all kip's in the company
- · Leadership between 10 to 20 persons
- · Achievement all the goals about revenue, cost, and utilities
- · Development the professional grow of all my employees
- · I elaborated financial reports

Education

DATA SCIENCE ENGINEER | 2021-2024 | UNIVERSIDAD DEL VALLE DE MEXICO

ACCOUNTANT | 2000-2004 | UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL AUTONOMA DE MEXICO

Hard Skills

- · Python (Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, Scipy)
- R
- · SQL and NoSQL (MySQL, Postgress, MongoDB)
- · PowerBI and Tableu
- · Excel
- Programming Languages (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Node, React, Vue, Django, Express, NestJs)

Soft Skills

- · Critical thinking
- Analytic
- · Communication
- · Teamwork
- · Creative
- · Algorithmic thinking

Languages

- · English
- · Spanish (Native)

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nestor-jesus-ramirez-reyes/

Github

https://github.com/Nesjesramrey